Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number ninety six in this exercise, we are going to make
a Java program for marriage sort.
So we are going to implement the Java and Java, the merged sort algorithm.
We go to the to the algorithm package that we have created, create Java class and use Java class is
called Marriage Story.
So we create a new Java class here called Merge.
So by the way, we, you and you can download all of these source codes from the Resources folder on
our Udemy course under every exercise that we have created.
So back to our image served.
We start by merges do subgenres of array, and the first substrate is from what L2 am?
And the second array is from AMP +1 to OK.
OK.
So consider Wistia.
We start by making that merges the merge method.
This will merge two sub arrays
sub arrays of array.
OK.
The first one, the first array
is array at Index L two am.
This is the range and the second separate second sub array is ray from and plus one then s.
OK.
So we need to merge the two arrays.
End to and combine them into one.
Are they?
So I will create public void marriage methods that took into the interpretive myth and into array and
l.
So I need to merge all of the party meters now into the array.
And these are the indices is empty and all these are working as and in diseases.
So these are the first in this index L, the second index, M and M +1 to the third index, which is
we have added another.
OK, now the first step is to find this find sizes
of two sub and these could be merged.
And and one equal to minus L plus one and intend to be equal to
our minus.
OK.
This is the first size and this is the second size of the of the second subject.
Now we create to create them every event and this is the L array equal to new and an index and one and
one and invite em or we calculated as are you and at index and two.
OK.
These are the sizes and one and two.
These are being calculated from the indices is that we have used from the integers that we have best
as parameters inside this method.
So we have created them the temporary array and have the sizes here and one and two after we have calculated
the sizes in the previous step.
So three, we copy data to them over these four and equal to zero I less than N1 and i + + i
l array at L at index I is equal to that of a at index l + I.
This is the index so.
It may be kind of complex algorithm, but I want from you to simply divide your this algorithm into
steps, as I have done, find the sizes create temporary arrays according to these sizes, and don't
copy that data to dump arrays that we have.
Create an index equal to array from index L plus i.
So Index I index equal a rate at an Excel plus, so we have divided them from AL to AM and from AMP
+1 to.
OK.
We are just copying the data in the same way.
I will create a four and j equal to zero J.
Less than.
And to and J.
+, + J.
I need to make here
are at Index J equal to Avai at Index Am a plus one plus J.
OK, so this is what we do by copying the data temporary advice.
Remember, in the previous video, I have told you that these are in separate rate loops.
They are not nested loops.
OK.
We after we have copied the data into temporary arrays.
Now let's merge in the forces that merge FIR.
First step is merged data.
Emerged that the damp evidence first by initial and this is of the first and the second surprising and
I equal to zero and int j equal to zero.
No, since we are going to March, I need the initial indices of index of the Mercer Array as array.
So int k equal to n, I need to make it as an OK line.
I less than N1 and and and j less then and to the then we need to check if L Appendix II is less than
or equal to OD at Index J, then I need to make the array at Index K IG World and at index.
This is that copying and merging that to address else in the same way.
But here I need to use that K equal to are at Index J.
And I need to make J Plus Plus here in all the cases that make every iteration K plus plus, so increase
K by one.
Now, with the remaining elements of L array, if any, if there is any.
So while we are in the six step, six steps in the fifth steps.
OK.
Copy the remaining
elements of an array, if any.
OK, so we use wide in the same way I less than one because I compare it with N1 and the J compare it
with and two sixes.
These are the variables, and these are the key to understand this algorithm.
I +, + + + + there.
The step number six is copied, the remaining elements of or, if any.
So we are going to check in the same way while while I we need to use to replace J and using J, we
need to compare it with N to.
So while J, we need array at Index K Equal are at Index I J +, + + + +.
OK.
This is the function that we have used to manage their arrays.
Now let's implement that function, that the main function that sorts out as a using the merge so public
WI.
This is the second method that we use in order to make and implement the sort algorithm.
Public void marriage sorting for what?
Or this array integrity and we have n n and we have in oh so f l less than R, we find the middle point.
Find the middle boy and equal to L plus or minus L of two truth we have dividing this into two.
We have found that the middle order minus left right minus left over two plus.
No, we sought their first and second sorted first and second halves
we call sort.
We called the method.
This this method merge sorting again because we have told you that we need to use the recursion.
We start by passing array left from index to middle.
This is from index left to middle and then from merged sorting, merge sorting.
Again, we called array from M +1 to are this out of the second half because left to middle and the
front middle, +1 to art.
These are the two halves we have sought them.
Now we need to merge them, merge that sorted halves by calling them merge function that we have created
previously and passing L as the left middle, as the middle and R as a right.
OK, now we need to create a utility function to print the array of size and so public static void trends
and as they.
And an equal array of conduct, length and forge and equal to zero I less than and and I last class.
So class plus I think we need to make system that our brand an asset and class space.
No, I make here system that the plant and a new know in order to test the code testing that code public
static void main i first string args array we use and hardly equal to.
Oops.
OK.
These are the numbers that are going to.
Sort.
And now I will create and merge sort object, Jack, sort of the new master.
They use the functions.
So merge, sort dot.
Sort of sorting the other there from index zero, we start from index zero array the length minus one.
OK.
This is the left and this is the right.
Now we print out the print and that every
print.
Ray Hadley, let's run and see.
Yeah.
On the previous.
We have an.
An error here, if J.
Less than an overt or less than and to so if j less than and to array at index gay equal rate at index
check.
OK, not.
OK.
Because we are talking about.
So here are the sort that the sorted elements of the array.
This is the array that we have best.
And these are the sort that elements using the.